以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
所以我有一些我要做的事情清单
so I've got a little list of things I'm
我希望今天能开始做几件事
hoping to do today I'll begin with a few
关于马鞍的最后一句话
final words about saddle points the
我之所以对马鞍点感兴趣
reason I'm interested in saddle points
是我们深入学习的时候
is when we get to this deep learning
方向你知道那一大步
direction you know that the big step
找到最低成本
there is finding a minimum of the cost
总成本函数和梯度下降
total cost function and gradient descent
肯定会讨论的是
which will certainly discuss is the
通常的方法或随机半径
usual method or stochastic radius
梯度下降和各种问题
gradient descent and all kinds of issues
如果你有一个马鞍会发生什么
arise what happens if you have a saddle
指向或退化和
point that's or or degenerate and
最小化所有这些可能性和
minimum all these possibilities and the
对深度学习的理解是
understanding of deep learning is is
重点越来越多地又有什么
focusing more and more on what does that
梯度下降算法产生如此我
gradient descent algorithm produce so I
只是想到马鞍极小和马克西玛我们
just thought saddle minima and Maxima we
了解鞍点是善良的
know about saddle points are kind of a
有些模糊呃权等等，所以这是什么
little hazy er right so so what this is
一个完美的例子，我只想说一个
a perfect example and I'll just say a
关于它的更多话，我想
few more words about it then I want to
我大胆地谈论实验室三
talk about the lab three that I boldly
张贴在恒星和约
posted on the on stellar and also about
项目只是为了让你让我们思考
projects just to get you get us thinking
关于那些，然后我的真实
about those and then and then my real
今天和本周的数学主题是
math topic for today and this week is
统计学的基本思想
basic ideas of statistics
特别是协方差矩阵我
particularly the covariance matrix I'm
确定你已经达到了平均值和方差
sure you've met mean and variance those
是最常用的词，我们将使用
are the most used words and we'll use
他们再后来我想去上
them again but then I want to go on to
协方差好，这就是即将发生的事情
covariance okay so that's what's coming
今天马鞍上的几句话点了很多
today a few words on saddle points a lot
关于实验室和任何你的话
of words about the lab and anything you
可以想问一下项目然后
can want to ask about projects and then
一些基本统计没关系
some basic statistics okay
马鞍点所以我正在采取的例子
saddle point so the example I'm taking
这是瑞利商，我正在服用
is this Rayleigh quotient and I'm taking
一个简单的矩阵我不妨拿一个
a simple matrix s I might as well take a
对角矩阵因为我可以我是
diagonal matrix because I can I it's
当然是对称的和任何对称的
symmetric of course and any symmetric
矩阵我可以改变变量
matrix I could just change variables by
Q矩阵和正交矩阵得到
a Q matrix and orthogonal matrix to get
到那样的东西，然后是X.
to something like that and then the X
我们在3d中，所以我们得到了一些
we're in 3d so we got a sort of
这里管理的规模和X矢量
manageable size here and the X vector is
UVW所以这是商X转置
UVW so this is the quotient X transpose
你看到的X恰好是5uSquared的3
X you see is just exactly 5u Squared's 3
v平方和1平方，我分开
v Squared's and 1 w squared and I divide
通过长度使事情正常化
by the length to normalize things so
我们知道的主要事实是什么？
what are the main facts that we know
与我不是要证明，但
with that I'm not going to prove but
什么是主要的事实是什么
what are the main facts what's the
R的最大值是最小值
maximum value of R what's the minimum
该函数的R值是否存在
value of R of that function and is there
一个马鞍点，所以马鞍是可以的
a saddle point so saddle up are ok
什么是最大价值有多大
what's the maximum value how large could
你把那个比率设为大写R我就是
you make that ratio capital R I just
认为你知道这不是一个标准
think you know this isn't a standard
1806年的主题，但它有一个例子
topic in 1806 but it with an example
像这样你会看到重点
like this you'll see the whole point
好吧，我有多大可以做R
okay so how large could I make R
继续说它是西格玛1而不是什么
go ahead and say it Sigma 1 and but what
在这里让我们来做这些
is it here let's just do with these
数字我可以达到多大比例
numbers how big can I make that ratio or
以及uvw的选择是什么让它变得更大
and and what choice of uvw makes it big
所以我能得到多大就是那个
so how big I can get it is 5 that that
比例不能超过5个，你看它
ratio can't be more than 5 you see it
将是5好我怎么得到5
would be 5 well how do I get to 5
R的最大值是5，什么是UVW
maximum of R is 5 and what is the UVW
所以我会说选择什么
that that so I'll say at what choice of
uvw会给你我们5你看到它
uvw would give us 5 here you you see it
马上100然后呢
immediately 1 0 0 and what about the
至少我们这个比率的最小值
minimum of our the minimum of this ratio
我怎么能把这个比例做得很好我
how do I make that ratio small well I
把我装载什么东西进入W代替
put I load stuff onto W instead of
把它加载到你的右边就是这样
loading it up on to you right it's just
很清楚究竟什么是最小值
it's clear so what is the minimum value
我们的1因为我会加载一切
of our 1 because I'll load everything
进入W所以最小值为1
into W so the minimum value will be 1
而那将是在向量001我
and that'll be at the vector 0 0 1 I've
把所有东西装在那里然后在那里
loaded everything there and then at the
这个简短的讨论的点是
point of this short discussion is is
还有另一个地方
there another place where the
AR的衍生物一阶导数是
derivatives first derivatives of AR are
所有这就是那个当然的地方
all 0 that's that's where of course the
一阶导数最大为0
first derivatives are are 0 at the max
在最后但我们也有3
at the min but we also we have we have 3
变量在这里，我们将找到
variables here and we're going to find
第三点，什么是点
the third point and what is that point
你可能猜到了，会是什么
you probably guess and what will be the
马鞍价值所以你必须看到一些
saddle value so so you have to see some
我想是什么样的表面
kind of a surface that that I guess what
我们是4d所以我们有矢量
are we in 4d so we have we have vectors
我们有基准坐标UVW和r
we have base base coordinates UVW and r
垂直，我们绘制表面
goes vertically and we plot that surface
我们并不真正理解它，除非
and we don't really understand it unless
我们想到了很多我们没有的东西
we think a lot about it which we haven't
但
but
我们可以很好地猜测是什么和
we can pretty well guess what's what and
你认为马鞍的价值是什么？
so what do you think is the saddle value
它将在何处达成
and where is it going to be reached
每个人都会正确地告诉我
everybody's going to tell me correctly
马鞍价值将是三
saddle value would be three at this
中间点很好，而且和这些是什么
middle point okay and and these what are
这三个关于矩阵
these three with respect to the matrix
它们是它的特征向量
they're its eigenvectors what are these
关于矩阵的三个数字
three numbers with respect to the matrix
它们就像它的特征值一样
they're its eigenvalues it's just like
这就是瑞利商的原因
that's why that Rayleigh quotient is
如此重要的功能，它是一种
such an important function it's kind of
如果你采取它的混乱功能
a messy function if you take its
衍生物，你知道你必须使用
derivative you know you've got to use
商数规则或使用呻吟声
the quotient rule or or use the groans
乘数使它成为通往的方式
multiplier to make it that's the way to
让它更易于管理，但它有点像
make it more manageable but it's kind of
凌乱但结果不可能
messy but the results could not be
更好的值有在
better the the values there are the
这些和地方的特征值
eigenvalues on these and the places
你到达他们的地方是
where you reach them are the
特征向量，因此最大值是最大的
eigenvectors and so the max is the most
这很重要，因为这是西格玛的一个
important so this is that's Sigma one
这是Sigma三或让lambda和
here's Sigma three or let lambda and
Sigma因为矩阵是对称的
Sigma because the matrix is symmetric
肯定的，在中间
positive-definite and here in the middle
是Sigma2，如果我们想要计算的话
is Sigma 2 and if we want to compute
得到的特征值和特征向量
eigenvalues and eigenvectors getting the
最大的一个或最小的一个是很多
largest one or the smallest one is a lot
比获得更快更普遍
quicker and in general than getting
这些中间你必须得到你
these ones in the middle you have to you
知道使用好的代码并支付
know use good codes and and pay
注意计算他们的马鞍
attention to computing their saddle
点数值所以我有什么好看的
point values so is there anything nice I
可以用马鞍点怎么做
can do with saddle points how does how
可以一个人如何思考
could one how does one think about
马鞍点
saddle points
所以再次定义鞍点
so again saddle point is defined by
第一
first
衍生物等于零和那个
derivatives equal zero that's and the
二阶导数没问题就是这样的
second derivatives okay so that's that's
这里的女主人是渐变的矢量
a matron here's a vector the gradient
矢量有两条河流尊重你
vector there two rivers respect to you
RDW中的相应V只是一个
that a respective V in the RDW just a
矢量，他们都是那些
vector and they're all all those
组件是梯度向量的0
components are 0 the the gradient vector
是0但是二阶导数呢？
is 0 but what about second derivatives
嗯，这是获得更多他们很多
well that's getting more they're a lot
那里有九个，因为我有
there nine of those now because I've got
你是二阶导数吗？
are you you second derivative with
尊重你，然后我，但我
respect to you second and then but I've
得到混合衍生二阶导数
got mixed derivative second derivative
R对你来说DV是这样的
of R with respect to do you DV so I have
一个三乘三矩阵
a three by three matrix
幸运的是，矩阵是对称的
fortunately that matrix is symmetric
因为我们有我们的祝福那
because we have we're blessed by that
奇妙的事实，导数与
wonderful fact that the derivative with
相对于U然后V与V相同
respect to U and then V is the same as V
然后你就这样我们得到一个对称的
and then you so we get a symmetric
矩阵，它很好，我不会写它
matrix and it's well I won't write it
虽然它会有一个你
down but it's it's going to have a you
知道它会有最大值
know will it's got there is a maximum
最小和鞍座信息
minimum and and saddled information
在这里建造这是另外一种
built in here's this one additional sort
我想谈谈马鞍
that I want to communicate about saddle
点，因为它真的很高兴
points because it's really nice to
不知何故回到最大值和最小值等等
somehow get back to maxima and minima so
我们的想法这个想法鞍
the idea of us this idea for a saddle
要点是能够把它写成
point is to be able to write it as the
在某种程度上是最小的，是的
maximum of a minimum in a way yeah so
让我这样做，然后我就完成了
let me do that and then I'm all done
好的
okay
所以我会说，拉姆达到
so I'm going to say that lambda to that
值是某事物的最大值
value is the maximum of over something
最低限度的
of the minimum over something of
我们的功能的极端可以
extremes of our of our function okay
那很好我必须告诉你什么
that's nice I have to tell you what
你正在最大限度地发挥你的作用
you're maximizing over and what you're
尽量减少，但这个想法是
minimizing over but that's the idea is
进入中间的一种方式
that one way to get into the middle
中间的地方那里有马鞍
middle of place there where the saddles
坐着是最多的一个
are sitting is to have a maximum of a
最小的，这就是我所领导的
minimum and that leads this what I'm
即将在这里完成将带领你
about to complete here would lead you
例如很快就到了
for example very quickly to the
我谈到的隔行扫描定理
interlacing theorem that I spoke about
对于特征值或对于奇异值
for for eigen values or and for singular
当你打扰或什么时候你的价值观
values of when you perturb s or when you
扔掉你的一排列
throw away a row and column of s you you
特征值介于两者之间
the eigen values go in between that is
那种结论，这最大最小的
the kind of conclusion that this max-min
东西设置为生产所以这里让
stuff is set up to produce so here let
我只是告诉你这将是我
me just tell you what it would be I'm
旨在让lambda好起来，所以我
aiming to get lambda to okay so I'm
最大限度地要做到两个
gonna take a maximum over to be a two
维空间子空间
dimensional spaces sub subspaces
r3的子空间我们在3d中，所以我就是你
subspaces of r3 we're in 3d so I'm you
可以看到那种像两个
can see that sort of like two
维度空间让我给出了
dimensional spaces let me give that
子空间有一个像V的名字啊是啊那个
subspace a name like V ah yeah that'll
做猫V每个人都可以看到那是一个
do cat V everybody can see that that's a
卡菲和那么这将是最低的
caffee and then this will be the minimum
卵巢，所以它是有点棘手的
ovaries so it's um it's kind of tricky
所以我采取任何子空间
so I take any subspace that's
二维，我会拿一个
two-dimensional and I'll take one in a
那一刻，我会找出最小
moment and I'll figure out the minimum
假设我选择了男子的子空间V.
suppose I take the subspace V whose men
它是由前两个跨越的
which is spanned by the first two it's
应该是一个跨越的二维子空间
supposed to be a 2d subspace spanned by
第一个假设我尝试示例
the first suppose I try example example
其他的跨度为100和010
the span of 1 0 0 and 0 1 0 in other
单词所有向量uv0这是一个2d
words all vectors u v 0 that's a 2d
空间确定最小的是什么
space ok what is the minimum of that
瑞利商指那两个
Rayleigh quotient over that two
维度空间所以现在我正在服用
dimensional space so now I'm taking a
至少我没有必要考虑
minimum I don't have to think about
马鞍点所以我很喜欢我
saddle points so I'm in all so I'm
看着同样的但是我已经W但是0
looking at the same but I've but W is 0
现在每个人都看到了我的意思
now everybody sees that that I've
将它压缩到2d所以W为0就是这样
squeezed it down to 2d so W is 0 what so
什么是最低限度，所以这个
what is the minimum now so so this this
事情会成为这个空间会
thing would become for this space would
成为5u平方和3V
become the 5 u squared and the 3 V
在平方加上B平方
squared over the u squared plus the B
平方
squared
但是W是0所以最小值是0
but the W is 0 so what's the minimum of
那33好的
that 3 3 ok
这个特殊的最小值是3
the minimum is 3 for this particular
空间让我称之为V特殊
space let me call it V special that for
该特定空间最小为3
that particular space the minimum is 3
正确的每个人都看到了因为我
correct everybody sees that because I
只需要U和V来玩5和
just have U and V to play with the 5 and
3如果我把所有东西都放入VI中
the 3 so if I put everything into V I
到达3，现在我采取最大值
get to the 3 and now I take the maximum
所以我已经了解到这一点
so so I've learned that this so the
最大值至少为3，因为这个
maximum is at least 3 because this
特别选择V给了我
particular choice of V gave me the
回答3，现在我采取了最大化
answer 3 and now I'm taking the maximum
在所有可能的2d空间和
over all possible 2d spaces and
当然我有三个为一
certainly I got three for one of the
我和V的可能空间可能会得到
possible spaces of V and I might get
对于其他一些人来说高于三个但是
higher than three for some other one but
实际上我没有
actually I don't
事实是，这将证明，以
the truth is that the this turns out to
三个这当然是什么
be three which is of course exactly what
我们想要，所以我说这个
we wanted so I'm saying that this
特别是二维空间
particular two dimensional space the
最小值超过最小值
minimum of over that minimum the minimum
有三个，现在我最大化了
there is three and now I maximize over
所有其他人，所以这个想法就是这样
all others and and so the idea is that
对于任何其他人，最小值将
for any other one the minimum value will
低于三，所以当我去
be below three and therefore when I go
对于最多的分钟，我得到三分钟，所以我
for the max of the mins I get three so I
重复一遍，然后保持沉默
just repeat that and then be quiet about
整个主题，所以它是最大的
this whole subject so it's a maximum
超过子空间
over subspaces
如果，瑞利商的最小值
of a minimum of the Rayleigh quotient if
子空间完全是完美的
that subspace is exactly the perfect
选择这个我得到的价值三
choice this one I get the value three
我声称这是最大的
and I'm claiming that's the biggest
我能得到的价值，因为如果我挑选任何
value I can get because if I pick any
其他子空间
other subspace
如果我选择假设的子空间怎么办？
what if I pick the subspace that suppose
假设另一个V将是所有向量
suppose another V would be all vectors
0vw
什么是最小的我会
what would be the minimum what would I
得到的最低的这件事情，但
get for the minimum of this thing but
现在W在图片中而U不在
now W is in the picture and U is not in
图片你会得到我的
the picture what would I get for the
至少我会得到一个
minimum there what I'd get one the
最小的是，当我把一切
minimum would be when I put everything
进入W，我得到了一个，然后当我
into W and I got one and then when I
取最大值这不是一个赢家是
take the max it's not a winner it's
抛出胜利者就是那个
thrown out the winner will be the that
空间和三个所以我想我
space and the three so I guess I'm
希望你能看到这一点
hoping that you sort of see in this
你可以表达这个的小例子
small example that you can express this
中间马鞍值因为它是合理的
middle saddle value as it's reasonable
在某些人看来它是最大的
think of it as a maximum in some
方向和最低限度
directions and a minimum
另一个想到好的尝试思考
another think of the well try to think
一些表面的这是在往上走
of some surface which is going up in
某些方向因此它是最小的
some directions so it's a minimum in
这些方向和它的下降在
those directions and it's going down in
其他方向因此它是最大的
other direction so it's a max in those
方向和萨罗点只是栖息
directions and Salo points just perched
在那个地方的那个地方
in there at that right at that place at
你知道如果你喜欢的马鞍点
the saddle point you know if you're like
从这里徒步到加利福尼亚或
hiking from here to California or
那里的东西是怎么回事你要
something there's going you're going to
通过一个马鞍点实际上你看到它
pass a saddle point actually you see it
他们在MassPike是一个惊人的
on them at the Mass Pike is an amazing
小小的一点我不知道是否
little little sign I don't know if
如果你开车向西你已经注意到了这一点
you've noticed it if you drive west on
远足或西部的质量派克
the Mass Pike pretty far or west of
波士顿有一个小标志说
Boston there's a little sign saying
告诉你海拔高度
telling you the altitude or elevation
什么，它说这就是
whatever and it says there this is the
最高点，直到你到达
highest point until you reach the
落基山脉基本上就是这样，好吧
Rockies basically that's it like okay
中西部地区相当平坦，因为
Midwest is pretty flat right and because
这是一个很长的路，你不认为
that's a long way away you don't think
马萨诸塞州就像真的一样
of Massachusetts as like really in the
有很高分的大联盟，但有它
big league with high spots but there it
是
is
它是最高的，直到你得到我
it's the highest one until you get and I
认为它告诉你下一个在哪里
think it tells you where where the next
无论如何，一个人将在科罗拉多州
one will be in Colorado anyway those
最高点往往是马鞍
highest points are tend to be saddles
最高点在哪里
the very very highest point where is
在阿拉斯加或那个地方
that in Alaska or somewhere that that's
根据定义，当然最大但是那里
a max of course by definition but there
在其他方面有很多马鞍点
are a lot of saddle points in in other
地方和那些将是千里马
places and those would be Maxima of
minima或minimaMaxima好我
minima or minima Maxima good I'm
停在那里我们可能会再次看到这一点
stopping there we might see this again
当我们开始梯度下降但是在
when we start a gradient descent but at
至少是因为马鞍点不来
least because saddle points don't come
我想，在微积分教学方面做了很多
up much in teaching calculus I thought
这是很好的好吗
that was good okay
第二点是模型实验室3和
second point is models lab 3 and
预测你想问的任何事情
projects anything you'd like to ask
关于项目所以请这是你的
about projects so please this is your
有机会问你也可以问
chance to ask you could also ask by
如果您有建议或，请通过电子邮件通知您
email you if you have a suggested or
一个项目的想法让我鼓励你
idea for a project let me encourage you
或者一个团队来处理它或只是你自己
or a team to work on it or just yourself
如果你想认为我可以得到
and if you want to think ok shall I get
这听起来有些反馈
some feedback of does this sound
明智的任何建议发给我一个
sensible any suggestions send me an
电子邮件
email
是的，我会很高兴，因为我是一个
yeah I'll be happy to because I'm a
我创建时也是初学者
total beginner here too when I created
这个实验室3我非常绝望
this lab 3 I was like desperate not for
您看过模型1的模型1
model 1 for model 1 have you looked at
这是它的在线它已达到
the it's online it's it's reached
恒星
stellar
它只是人们打印的一页
it's only one printed page the people
看看这个
had a look at this
所以我只是快速重复模型1
so I'll just repeat quickly model 1 is
是一个过度拟合的例子
is a example where of overfitting and
和模型1发生了什么
and what's going on with model 1 so
模型一说五取就够了
model one says take five would be enough
但我可能会说10或者其他什么
but I probably said 10 or something so
我会把它分为六分并放
I'll make it six points and put
近似通过它们曲线如此
approximate put a curve through them so
如果你画一条曲线而曲线是
if you put a curve and the curve is
将成为一个多项式，所以我们要去
going to be a polynomial so we're going
以适应它适合由多项式大家
to fit it fit by by polynomial everybody
知道多项式是Cnaught加C1X.
knows polynomial is C naught plus C 1 X
加上K的所有CKX让我们说
plus whatever C K X to the K let's say
好的
okay
因为K等于零我不知道我是不是
for K equals zero well I don't know if I
甚至问零是最好的
even asked zero that would be the best
直线将会运行
straight line that would be run along
的平均K值等于一，这将是
the average k equal to one that would be
一条直线适合你
a straight line fit and you would
计算通过这些正方形，因为
compute that by these squares because of
当然，我们没有直线打算
course our no straight line is going to
通过你要去的所有要点
go through all the points you're going
通过最小二乘法得到一些错误
to have some error by least squares to
将再用抛物线装配
would be fitting by a parabola again
你会有一些错误但是因为更小
you'll have some error but smaller since
抛物线包括直线所以你
parabolas include straight lines so you
只能减少总平方和
can only reduce total sum of squares
进入2级3级的错误
error by going to degree 2 degree 3 and
多达多少分，所以我们采取12让
up to how many points so we take 1 2 let
我只是使用我用过的同一封信
me just use the same letter I've used
这可能是哦哦，MM是
here probably of oh well the M M is the
点数但M在两者之间变化
number of points but M varies between
有一点我猜，而且可能是一个
one point I guess and and probably an
终点是啊或者K可以达到最高点
end point yeah or maybe K up to up to up
最多六个让我们说好，我想要
to up to six let's say okay and I want
对六个没有五个发表评论
to make a comment about six no five
会这样做不会5度5适合
would do it won't 5 degree 5 will fit
六点，我们得到六分
the six points that we've got six points
在这里，但如果我停止五年级，我就是
here but if I stop a degree five I was
因为5次多项式更好
better there because degree 5 polynomial
也有一个恒定的术语，所以它真的
also has a constant term so it really
有六个系数，所以有一个学位
has six coefficients so there's a degree
有一个1度5的多项式，有六个
there's a 1 degree 5 polynomial with six
数字六个系数是去
numbers six coefficients that goes
通过这六点，它就是这样
through those six points and it so it's
完美契合
a perfect fit
这将是该数据的精确配合，以便
that would be exact fit of the data so
这里的数据创建了一个多项式
here's the data create a polynomial of
5级，通过这些点
degree 5 that goes through those points
确切地看看结果和什么
exactly and look at the result and what
你会看到什么
what would you see
如果你看看结果会是
if you look at the result would it be
顺便说一下，这是多项式的
smooth of course it's a polynomial would
很好
it be nice
没有这将是可怕的，它会得到
no it'll be horrible it'll to get
通过这些点我得到六点
through those points did I get six
点是的，以通过这些点
points yeah to get through those points
我猜那个五度
I'm guessing that that fifth degree
多项式完美拟合就是一个例子
polynomial the perfect fit is an example
实际上每个人都会发生这种情况
that occurs to practically everybody of
过度拟合，因为这样做
overfitting because do that making that
决定
decision
完美契合学习数据
perfect fit learn that learn the data
训练数据正是我们要派
training data exactly we'll send the
多项式我不知道它的样子
polynomial I don't know what it looks
喜欢
like
我不想要，但我确实想知道
I don't want well I do want to know but
不管怎样，现在还不是疯狂的
not right now anyway craziness and of
当然，我要问这样的
course I'm going to ask like that
可能我会要求你策划
probably I'm gonna ask you to plot the
结果是什么是最小的方块
results well what's the least squares
当你用直线拟合时会出错
error when you fit by a straight line
当你适合水平时适合
when you fit when you fit by horizontal
由直线排列的恒定配合
line a constant fit by a straight line
拉升至抛物线向上移动到生成立方体
move up to parabolas move up to cubics
但是当你击中它时你不是
but when you hit the hit this you're not
你知道自己犯了任何错误
making any error at all you know you're
不是真的需要使用这些方块
not really needing to use these squares
你能解决斧头等于BAC会
you could solve ax equal B a C will be
等于B所以这些是B的东西
equals B so these this is the B thing
C是系数的向量
and C is the vector of of coefficients
和矩阵A是个坏消息时，它的
and the matrix a is bad news when it's
6x6，当你完全适应
6x6 when you get up to a complete fit
我想我想要看到的东西
and I guess what I want to just to see
是很多我不知道的事情
is a lot of things I don't know like
假设我将6改为20或其他什么
suppose I change 6 to 20 or something
然后我很确定不会外出
then I'm pretty sure that not out out
那里是181920这件事真的
there at 18 19 20 this thing is really
离开地图，你可以
off the map and you could you could
计算它的最大值，你会看到一个非常的
compute its max and and you'd see a very
大数
big number
但我当然不知道在哪里
but I don't know where but of course for
一条漂亮的直线
a straight line that would be pretty
安全的斜坡将是相当温和的
safe the slope would be pretty moderate
我不知道你在哪儿
and I don't know where are you so so
这可能不适合尝试
that's probably under fitting to try to
这是一条直线，这就是它
fit this by a straight line it's it's
没有你想要的那么接近但是
not as close as you would want but
装配完全完美贴合高
fitting by a full perfect fitting high
度多项式当然是
degree polynomial is certainly
过度拟合哪里是边界
overfitting where where is the boundary
我相信人们都知道这件事，但我
I'm sure people know about this but I
认为这是我们可以学到的东西
think it is something we could learn
从不过就是这样一个模型是什么
from so that's what that model one is
关于并且只是做出最后的评论
about and just to make one final comment
矩阵a在案例中有一个名称
that matrix a has a name in the case
你在哪里它是一个方阵
where you're where it's a square matrix
你完全适合的地方
where you're fitting exactly
插值我会是这样的
interpolating I would be the word so
那就是完全符合对应的
there so that exact fit that corresponds
方阵a和它的字
to square matrix a and the word for it
是插值，我猜它就像
is interpolation and I guess it's like
错了再次看到那个家伙
wrong again seeing that guy too often
在这里它就像呻吟声
here so it'd be like groans
插值但矩阵有一个
interpolation but the matrix has a
不同的名称和名称
different name and whose name is
与该矩阵vandermonde相关联
associated with that matrix vandermonde
vandermonde所以这是方阵
vandermonde so this is the square matrix
这是让我这样写的
which was so let me write it this is
称为vandermonde矩阵，它就是
called a vandermonde matrix and and it's
有一个疯狂大的矩阵
the matrix that has a crazy large
因为正如我所说的那样
inverse because just as I'm saying the
从完美的契合中看出来
see that comes out from the perfect fit
来自广场的插值
from the interpolation from the square
矩阵C的将是巨大的，因此
matrix the C is going to be giant and so
您
you
你能说得对，你能够
you could right you'll be able to you
你将构建一个矩阵
you you will construct a matrix of
当然要做到这一点，它会
course to do this and it will be
与供应商完全相同，所以我们听说过
identical to the vendor so we've heard
这个词vandermonde矩阵在此
this word vandermonde matrix in this
上周上课
class within the last week
任何人记住这个词的位置
anybody remember where the word
范德蒙德上课了
vandermonde came up in class it was in
汤森教授的讲座让你如此
professor Townsend's lecture so you
如果你可以回到那个视频
could go back to that video if you
想要作为矩阵的一个例子
wanted as an example of matrix which
这是一个可怕的逆转巨人
which had a horrible inverse a giant
矩阵Hilbert矩阵是另一个
matrix the Hilbert matrix was another
例子我认为他做了两个例子
example I think he did two examples
范德蒙和希尔伯特等等无孔
vandermonde and Hilbert so ventless
vandermonde矩阵我可以写下来
vandermonde matrix i could write it down
但你会留给你一个大的
but you'll leave that to you has a big
逆，它的特征值是什么
inverse and it's its eigenvalues what no
奇异的价值因为它不是
singular values because it's not
对称的奇异值是方式
symmetric its singular values are way
分散你知道它有点小
scattered you know it has tiny little
奇异值加上普通尺寸
singular values plus an ordinary size
奇异值，这就是例子
singular values so that's the example
我只是觉得，你可以与去
that I just think you could go with and
据我可以看到你把它发送到
as far as I can see you sending it to
作为朱莉娅文件的自动编程器，它将是均匀的
autograder as a Julia file it'll be even
比平时差将其发送到
worse than usual sending it to
autograder
他们不会认为它不会知道什么
they won't I think it wouldn't know what
这样做，据我看到，所以我
to do as far as I can see so I'm
想一些即将到来的提交
thinking of some submissions to coming
评分范围，我正在考虑一些
to grade scope and I'm thinking of some
图表显示K发生了什么
plots to show what happens as K
增加和一些数据表可能
increases and some tables of data maybe
然后可能的一个段落
and then maybe a paragraph of of
结论如何安全程度
conclusion like how what degree is safe
什么时候变得有风险？
and when does it become risky and when
它会变成灾难吗？
does it become disaster so stuff like
这才是真正的这些
that that's it's really these are sort
开放式实验室和你使用任何
of open-ended labs and and you use any
语言
language
关于那个例子的问题是
questions about that example which is
真的，这就是我期待到
really that's what I'm expecting to to
做好准备并且相当不错
be ready and and and quite quite a good
休息后的星期三的例子
example for Wednesday after the break
无论如何你甚至可以提出什么问题
what question are anyway you could even
给我发电子邮件你可能看到他们可以看到
email me you probably see they could see
那个模型看起来是什么样的
what what that model looks like then
第二个我第一次跳
second one I've taken the first jump
进入网络做了一个非常简单的网络
into networks made a very simple network
没有很多没有任何隐藏
without a lot of without any hidden
层实际上只是写了
layers at all actually and just wrote
我觉得可能有用，但你可以
down what I think might work but you may
发现你想修改模型去
find that you want to modify model to go
为此，我没有任何专利或
for it I I don't have any patent or
模式二的个人利益是
personal stake in the way model two is
写的，但这个想法适合数据和
written but the idea is fit data and
我们将从数据开始但不做到
we'll start with data but don't make it
太完美了，因为我们不想要我们
too perfect because we don't want we
想要一些学习在这里发生等等
want some learning to happen here and so
所以它是分类问题所以它
so it's the classification problem so it
并不是最小的方格与它
won't be least squares with a with it
使用U，V和W这样的变量
with variables like U and V and W it's
只加1或减1或10或猫和
just plus 1 or minus 1 or 1 0 or cat and
狗无论分类如此
dog whatever the classification is so
这就是启动基本的基本问题
that's the basic basic problem to start
与深入学习相当
with in deep learning to for quite a
很长一段时间这就是自然的问题，所以
long time that's the natural problem so
这是一个分类问题和
it's a classification problem and the
这里的描述提出了一种设定方法
description here suggests one way to set
提取训练数据并执行
up the training data and and execute a
神经网络一样通过实验
neural net like experiment by
-但没有离得很远
- but without getting very far away from
普通-线性代数是的，所以你如果
ordinary - linear algebra yeah so you if
你要我说，如果你想
you want as I say if you wanted to
改变这种发展它进一步得到一些
change this develop it further get some
关于它的想法就是那个是什么
ideas about it that's what that's what
重点在这里
the whole point is here
实际上是教师在这方面的会议
actually the faculty meeting on this
也许今天是星期三的今天
week maybe today what's today Wednesday
是的所以今天下午没有教职员工
yeah so it's this afternoon no faculty
并不是因为它而已
doesn't come to much but because it's
下午晚些时候，但教职员工
late in the afternoon but faculty
今天下午的会议是麻省理工学院
meeting this afternoon is about MIT
计划的要求或课程
plans for requirements or courses in
计算思维和某种方式
computational thinking and in a way this
在数学系当然是
course within the math department is
在其中的那些
among the ones that are in that
当然在其他部门的方向
direction of course in other departments
无论如何，这些都是进一步的
those are further along anyway when
rajarao去年春天教他的课程
rajarao taught the course last spring he
朱莉娅系统得到了更好的发展
had the Julia system better developed
并且，有这样一个机会，让
and and there was a chance to bring
电脑和携带笔记本电脑，并做
computers and bring laptops and do do
事情在课堂上，你将有
things in class and and you'll have that
当他在一次访问时再次有机会
chance again when he visits in in a
一个月好了，我很开心
month ok enough and and I'm open to
关于这个项目的问题我应该
questions about the project should I
也许会请你给我发一个粗略的想法
maybe ask you to email me a rough idea
一个项目并告诉我你是否在
of a project and tell me if you were in
一组或者，如果你想找到一个
a group or if you would like to find a
我可能是两三个人
group of maybe two or three people I'm
没有想到组五十两
not thinking of groups of fifty two or
其中3位是约明智的问题
three would be sensible questions about
项目我的意思是我刚刚介绍过这个
projects I mean I just introduced this
我们项目的想法
idea of our project
我为它而不是食物而道歉
and I apologize for it not the food not
这样做不会把它提起来
doing it that not bringing it up the
第一周，但我只是看不到我
first week but I just couldn't see I
不想在线性代数上做考试
don't want to do exams on linear algebra
我们通过了这一点，所以这似乎是
we passed that point so this seemed the
正确的方式，但我不是你知道我
right way to go but I'm not you know I'm
不在这里寻找博士论文
not looking for a PhD thesis here
问题想法我想我希望你
questions thoughts I guess I hope you
知道你可以问哦，好的将如何
know you can ask oh good right how will
我想是的，所以范围是相关的
I I think yeah so the scope is connected
到你投入的时间
to the time that you would devote to it
我应该怎么说范围
and what should I say about scope maybe
相当于三个作业或
the equivalent of three homeworks or
一些事情，因为我都会平息
something because I'll all tamp down
家庭作业说项目日期越来越近
homework says project date gets closer
不，我给你知道这是一个想法
does I give an idea that you know it's
它是如此，它不是无限的，但它是
it's so it's not not infinite but it's
不是微不足道的小事，是的好
not something tiny and trivial yeah good
好吧那就是没有的东西
well that's the thing there aren't
真的过去几年我们虽然是
really past years we are though we are
那些我们明年会有的
the ones so so we I will have next year
如果你贡献一些好主意也许
if you contribute some good ideas maybe
我应该问我
I should should I ask
按或退出可能会将项目发送给我们
press or out maybe send us the projects
他在密歇根州使用的是一些
he uses in Michigan that would be some
想法，但记住他做到了
ideas but remember that he does it
到目前为止还没有改变过程
hasn't up to now anyway moved the course
为了深入学习，他做了其他主题
toward deep learning he did other topics
所有这些都可以，但后来一些
all of which would be fine but then some
不少人有603六人
quite a few people have had some 603 six
或者对卷积有所了解
or know something about convolutional
神经网络
neural net
我很高兴能够做到这一点
and I'm certainly excited to get to that
主题所以项目可以到达那里或
topic so the project could get there or
它不可能都完全没问题
it could not both both totally fine okay
这是一个好主意，我会问拉吉
that's a good idea I'll ask Raj for just
项目，你会认识到
the projects and you'll recognize a
夫妻因为你做了一对夫妇
couple because you've done a couple but
他们是一群更是的，是的，那么
they're a bunch more yeah yeah then
还有另外一个问题，我
there was another question and I'm
记得那是我的想法
remembering that that there was I think
也许每个人都收到一封电子邮件，或
maybe everybody got an email or a
恒星公告称，一些
stellar announcement that that some
班上的成员采取了主动
members of the class took an initiative
这真是太棒了
which was wonderful to open the
人们出现的可能性
possibility of people just showing up
媒体实验室每周一个晚上
one evening a week in the Media Lab was
它或它是一个位置，并拥有它
it or did it was a location and has it
发生了或者它是未来的事件
happened or is it a future event it
发生好了
happened okay
但是我没有提到它的人
and but people I hadn't mentioned it in
所以可能你没有和
class so probably you didn't have and
还没有真正进入项目
were not really into projects yet so
这可能是一个安静的夜晚
what it was probably a quiet evening
是的，那是有成效的但是
yeah yeah and that's productive but
安静没关系
quiet okay
所以它会在春天之后再次发生
so will it happen again after spring
打破
break
好的，所以再次发布在恒星计划上
okay so post again on stellar plan for
人们可以来的下次会议
the next meeting that people could come
对啊，所以这是大卫和她的露面
to yeah so this is David and her turn up
那么你会认出他的名字
whoo so you'll recognize his name in
那里，你有没有参加会议
there and you did you have the meeting
在媒体实验室或没关系，好吧
in the Media Lab or okay okay so with
休息和春天有希望
the break coming and spring hopefully
在今天的潜在风暴之后来临
coming after today's potential storm
是的，当我们回来时，好的就是那个
yeah when we come back good okay is that
好，我希望一些这是很有帮助的你
good I hope some of that is helpful you
让你看到的一样多的想法
get an idea you're seeing about as much
我知道哪个是模特一个
as I know which is model one is
绝对做到了
definitely do
非常重要和范德蒙德
and very significant and vandermonde
矩阵易用等是真实的
matrix ease and so on are truly
重要的是他们的不稳定性很大
important and their instability is a big
问题，但然后走向权重和
issue but then moving toward weights and
并且培训数据和测试数据在哪里
and training data and test data is where
我们要去好确定，所以我有一些
we want to go good ok so do I have some
我只想谈谈意思和时间
time I do just to speak about mean and
变异的两个金字
variance the two golden words of
统计和协方差矩阵
Statistics and covariance the matrix the
线性代数与
the intersection of linear algebra with
统计然后一些着名的
statistics and then some famous
不平等所以我将继续
inequality so this I'll continue with
这个星期五和张贴一些
this on Friday and post some of the
材料，以便来自后来
material so that's coming from a later
一段笔记好吧，我可以谈谈
section of notes okay can I just talk
所以我要么有概率P1
about so I either have probabilities P 1
最多Pn加1或者我有
up to P n adding to 1 or I have a
持续分配概率
continuous distribution of probabilities
也许是从负无穷大的所有X的
maybe from all X's from minus infinity
到无穷远再次给予1让我的工作
to infinity again giving 1 let me work
与离散的例子在哪里
with the discrete example that's where
人们自然而然地开始，所以我有这样的
people naturally start so I have so what
是我的意思，所以我有可能
is the mean so I I've been possible
这些概率的结果和我
outcomes with those probabilities and I
我可以问你这个问题
can either I can ask you about the
样本意味着或者我可以问你关于
sample mean or I can ask you about the
预期意味着好，所以样本意味着
expected mean okay so the sample means
我们做了一些我们已经做过的实验
we've done an experiment we've got some
输出预期均值意味着我们知道
output the expected mean means we know
概率，但我们没有使用它们
probabilities but we haven't used them
然而
yet
所以那些
so those are
这是使用实际输出和
this is this uses actual output and the
样本意思就是让我为我
sample mean is simply let me shall I
对我说这两个是好的
just say em for me well these two are
重要的是不同的是数据
importantly different one is data is
你做过的事情
something where you've done the
实验，这是在你做之前
experiment and this is before you do the
实验和信件得到可能是Mew
experiment and the letters get maybe Mew
我已经改为Mew我不想用
I've changed to Mew I don't want to use
是因为S帮方差没关系使用
s because s gets used with variance okay
所以这只是平均水平
so so it's just the average average
样本的输出就像我翻转一样
output from the sample so like I flipped
一百万次硬币和输出
a coin a million times and the output
是0或1所以我有一百万和
was 0 or 1 so I got a million ones and
零和我取平均值而且我是
zeros and I take the average and I'm
期待一个像50万的数字
expecting a number like half a million
因为我正在想一个公平的硬币
because I'm thinking of a fair coin so
那个和大数法则会
that and the law of large numbers would
说这个样本意味着什么
say that that that this sample mean does
接近1/2，概率为1
approach 1/2 with probability 1 as the
样本的数目变大，从而样品
number of samples gets larger so sample
意思是直截了当的预期
mean is straightforward the expected
意思是指我们这些都是实际的
mean means we these are actual out
他们发生的样本输出而不是
sample outputs they happened whereas the
期望的意思是我将使用的
expected mean is just the and I'll use
因为这是它的概率
em for that it's it's the probability of
输出的第一个输出时间加
the first output times that output plus
第二次输出的概率
the probability of the second output
输出加上加P和X的时间没问题
times that output plus plus P and X okay
所以它将接近那个
so it's the that will approach that with
概率1就是这个数字
probability 1 as this this number
资本n注意差异资本
capital n notice the difference capital
这里是样本数量
n here is the number of sample
试验的数量和它得到大
the number of trials and it gets big
我们一直在做越来越多的事情
it's we keep doing things more and more
这就是这个小n是数字
this is just this little n is the number
可能的不同产出与他们的
of possible different outputs with their
概率，你看到它和
probabilities and there you see it and
当然在连续的情况下我们
of course in the continuous case we
将采用XDX的XP积分
would take the integral of X P of X DX
所以，我只想比喻一下
so let me just by analogy you should
知道连续版本是什么和
know what the continuous version is and
什么离散形式是好的这是
what the discrete version is ok that's
对于方差样本，现在的平均值还可以
the mean okay now for variance sample
差异，我应该说预期
variance and shall I say expected
方差我不知道只是方差
variance I don't know just variance it's
人们通常会说我不会
what people would usually say I don't
知道我在那里记得正确的话
know if I remember the right word there
样本差异我包含的是什么
sample variance what is that I included
线性代数书中的这个主题
this topic in the linear algebra book
无论如何
anyway
是的好，所以样本方差是什么
yeah okay so what's the sample variance
所以为什么我猜我是的所以是什么
so why I guess I'm yeah so what is the
样本方差什么是方差
sample variance what's the variance
无论如何，关键点是什么
about anyway what's the key point of
方差它是与平均值的距离
variance it's the distance from the mean
所以这将是一个距离
so will be this will be a distance from
样本均值，这将是一个
the sample mean and this will be a
距预期平均值的距离不是
distance from the expected mean so not
距离零距离，但距离mu
distance from zero but distance from mu
和M从中心的东西好吧
and M from the center of the thing okay
所以我们有了样本差异
so the sample variance so again we have
n样品，但出于一些奇妙的原因
n samples but for some wonderful reason
在统计数据中，你除以n减去1
in statistics you divide by n minus one
这个时间和原因有做
this time and the reason has to do with
你使用过这个的事实
the fact that you used one this will
涉及我的意思所以这将是
involve the me mean so this would be the
这将是第一个输出减去亩
this would be the first output minus mu
平方到第n个输出减去视图
squared up to the nth output minus view
这是平均距离
squared so it's the average distance
从你的平均距离
from you average squared distance from
你，但这有点扭曲
you but with this little twist that of
当n很大时，它不是很好
course when n is large it's not a very
n和n之间的显着差异
significant difference between n and n
减一，我认为这是正确的
minus one I think that's about right
这一切都是我只做一个
all this is that I'm just doing one
一遍又一遍地实验协方差
experiment over and over covariance
更深层次的想法是线性的
which is the deeper idea is where linear
代数进来我有一个矩阵，因为
algebra comes in I have a matrix because
为什么因为我做了几次
why because I'm doing several multiple
我同时做实验
experiments at the same time I'm
翻转两个硬币，我正在翻转十五个
flipping two coins I'm flipping fifteen
硬币我做其他的事情，所以让
coins I'm doing other things so so that
我正在做的时候会是协方差
will be covariances when I'm doing
几个实验将立即
several experiments at once that will
涉及到大小的矩阵这里这么
involve matrices of that size here so
什么是我应该的差异
what's the what's the variance I should
给你平常的符号
have given you the usual notation the
x的期望值是什么的
expected value of x that's what's the
意思是，在这里，我在看
mean and here I'm looking at the
什么时候我的预期价值
expected value of what so when I'm
使用概率计算方差
computing a variance using probabilities
所以我使用的期望不是-不是
so I'm using expectations not-not-not
试运行期望意味着使用
trial runs expectations means use the
概率和期望是什么
probabilities and what's the expectation
从X到平均值的距离
of the distance from X to the mean
方可以，那就是我什么时候
square okay and that is when I what I'm
期待一个离散的
doing an expectation for for a discrete
我想到了第一个概率
set I think of the probability the first
输出x1的概率
probability that goes with an output x1
和第二个概率
and a second probability that goes with
输出x2，每次减去
an output x2 and each time I subtract
从平均值和正方形好吧这样
from the mean and square okay so that's
每个人都称之为Sigma的差异
the variance that everybody calls Sigma
平方
squared
好的，现在还剩两分钟
okay now two minutes left
仅仅说两到几个就足够了
is it is enough to say two to a few more
有关协变的话在去
words about covariance over to get to
协方差我真的要说
covariance I really have to speak about
联合概率是一个吱吱作响的想法
joint probabilities that's a creaky idea
联合概率所以我做了两个
joint probabilities so I'm doing two
一次实验所以每个人都有它
experiments at once so each one has its
自己的可能性，但同时我也要
own probabilities but together I have to
问你知道所以这里有两个容易
ask you know so here here are two easy
案件假设我正在翻转两个硬币
cases suppose I'm flipping two coins so
我可能会得到头的头我可能会
that I might get heads heads I may get
尾巴尾巴尾巴或尾巴尾巴
heads tails tails heads or tails tails
是否有可能的产出
for possibility for possible outputs
可能的对没关系，如果我
there for possible pairs okay and if I
如果你正在翻转一枚硬币我就是
if you're flipping one coin and I'm
再翻一遍那些
flipping another one those are
那些是独立的结果
independent results those are
那里的独立结果不会有
independent results there there won't be
协方差所在的地方
a covariance where where some where
在哪里知道我的翻转是什么
where by knowing what my flip was I
会更了解你的翻转，但现在
would know more about your flip but now
胶粘剂的另一种可能性
the other possibility would be to glue
如果我翻转，硬币现在在一起
the coins together now if I do a flip
他们总是头上或头上或者
they always come up heads and heads or
尾巴和尾巴所以头尾巴
tails and Tails so the heads tails
事实上，组合是不可能的
combination is not possible in fact one
输出完全取决于另一个
output is totally dependent on the other
输出，这是我们的另一个极端
output so that's the other extreme we
具有协方差的独立输出
have independent outputs with covariance
0，我们完全依赖输出
0 and we have totally dependent outputs
其中一件事只是粘在上面
one of the things are just glued
当一个结果告诉我们什么时，一起
together when one result tells us what
另一个结果是那种情况
the other result is then that situation
在哪里
where the
协方差是最大不可能的
the covariance is a maximum couldn't be
比他们大，他们在民意调查中说
bigger than that and they say in polling
如果你拉一个家人说
if you were pulling a family say
政治民意调查就好了
political polling well there would be it
预期会有一些协方差
there would be some covariance expected
有两个或三个或五个人
there the two or three or five people
你住在同一栋房子里
that you living in the same house
不会完全独立
wouldn't be independent entirely
独立但他们也不会
independent but they nor would they
总是说所有五个都给出相同的答案
always say all five give the same answer
因此协方差矩阵将具有
so the covariance matrix would be have
一些非对角线，但它会
some off-diagonal but it would it would
实际上仍然是不可逆的
still be not invertible and actually
我想告诉你下一次
what i want to tell you about next time
一开始就是协方差矩阵
at the start is that covariance matrix
这是我来定义，你会
which i have to define for you would be
将是对称的正定或
will be symmetric positive definite or
或半确定什么是半
or semi definite what's the semi
当然是明确的情况
definite case of course that's the case
硬币粘在一起的地方是的
where the coins are glued together yeah
是的，好的，谢谢，那就是你
yeah okay thanks that's that's so you
我知道周五会发生什么
know what's coming Friday I know that
假期也在周五即将到来
holiday is also coming Friday and just
you'll make a good plan and I'll move on
你会制定一个好的计划，我会继续前进
休息后好
after the break good